Guide to the Victor Serge Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Materials Collected by Vlady Kibalchich, 1949-1994; Series VI; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - WRITINGS ABOUT SERGE
    - Brodziak, Emilio
      - "Trabajos de y sobre Víctor Serge," typescript (bound), 1994 (Box 22, Folder 677-678)
        Kibalchich Biografía de Víctor Serge (Chapter VII) by Richard Greeman
        Also includes: loose versions of
        some works
    - Calderón Rodriguez, Eligio
      - "Nota sobre Victor Serge," typescript (photocopy), 1980 (Box 22, Folder 679)
    - Castelnuovo, Elías
      - "Algo sobre Víctor Serge", 1990
    - Gorkin, Julián
      - "El último adiós", 1990
    - Greeman, Richard
      - Biografía de Víctor Serge (Chapter VII), translation by María Palomar and Emilio Brodziak, typescript, 1994 Apr
      - "Versiones de la historia: Boris Yeltsin, Víctor Serge y la rebelión de Kronstadt," typescript, 1994 Feb 10
      - "Victor Serge," typescript (photocopy), 1977 Aug (Box 22, Folder 680)
      - "Víctor Serge y Léon Trotski: relaciones, 1936-1940," typescript (photocopy), corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 681)
      - "Victor Serge's The Case of Comrade Tulayev ," typescript (photocopy), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 682)
    - Gutiérrez Alvarez, J.
      - "Víctor Serge: unas notas bibliográficas", 1990
    - Iglesias, Ignacio
      - "Apostillas a la carta de Víctor Serge a León Sedov", 1990
      - "El fin de Antonov-Ovseenko", 1990
    - Kibalchich, Vlady
      - "Erotemas socialistas," typescript, 1993 Jul 15
      - [Notes], holograph, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 683)
      - [Two untitled works], typescript, 1993-94
    - Labastida, Jaime
      - "A propósito de El caso Tuláyev ," typescript, 1993 Jul 22
    - Lefeuvre, René
      - "Adieu à Victor Serge", 1990
    - Maldoror, Sarah
      - "L'hopital de Leningrad," typescript (photocopy), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 684)
        Includes: inscription by author
    - Mendoza, Leo Eduardo
      - " El caso Tuláyev. Notas de lectura," typescript, 1993 Jul 15
    - Munguía Huato, Román
      - " El caso Tuláyev de Víctor Serge," typescript, n.d.
    - Mutis, Alvaro
      - "Salvación por la literatura", 1990
    - Páporov, Yuri
      - "Víctor Serge y su novela El caso Tuláyev ," typescript, 1993 Jun 24
    - Poniatowska, Paula
      - "Capítulo del 'caro Tulaev,'" typescript, corrected, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 685)
    - Ramírez Esteva, Jorge
      - "Kaleidoscopio del revolucionario Victor Serge," drafts, typescript and carbon, 1978 May (Box 22, Folder 686)
    - Shachtman, Max
      - "Homenatge a un combatent de la revolució", 1990
    - Various authors
      - "Dossier: diaris i revistes, centenari Victor Serge, 1890-1990," typescript (photocopy) (Box 22, Folder 687)
        "Materials sobre Víctor Serge"
        "Llamamiento internacional"
        "Adieu à Victor Serge" by René Lefeuvre
        "Homenatge a un combatent de la
        revolució" by Max Shachtman
        "Algo sobre Víctor Serge" by Elías
        Castelnuovo
        "Adèu a Andreu Nin" by Victor Serge
        "El recuerdo de Vladimir Illitch" by
        Victor Serge
        "La vida y la muerta de Leon Trotski"
        by Victor Serge
        "¿A dónde va Stalin?" by Victor Serge
        "Literatura de postguerra" by Victor
        Serge
        "Salvación por la literatura" by
        Alvaro Mutis
        "Asechanzas en España" by Victor Serge
        "Necesidad de una renovación del
        socialismo" by Victor Serge
        "El último adiós" by Julián Gorkin
        "Recuerdo" by Juan Andrade
        "Carta de Víctor Serge a Andrés Nin"
        "Carta de Víctor Serge a León Sedov"
        "Apostillas a la carta de Víctor
        Serge a León Sedov" by Ignacio Iglesias
        "Los escritos y los hechos" by Víctor
        "El fin de Antonov-Ovseenko" by
        Ignacio Iglesias
        "Carta de Vlady a Francisco de Cabo"
        "Víctor Serge: unas notas
        bibliográficas" by J. Gutiérrez Alvarez
      - Clippings of obituaries for Serge, 1947, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 688)
      - Clippings of biographical articles, 1950-92, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 689-691)
    - Unidentified authors
      - Advertisement for "Où va la révolution russe? L'affaire Victor Serge", [198-?] (Box 22, Folder 692)
      - [Notes], holograph, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 693)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Bondy, François. "La seule urgence," printed version, 1958 Aug (Box 22, Folder 694)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 7.6; (5 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folders 5, 19-20, 28, 32, 37, 40, 49, 78-79, 81, 90 (Box 23, Folder 695)
  - Box 3, folders 110, 120 (Box 23, Folder 696)
  - Box 4, folder 178 (Box 23, Folder 697)
  - Box 4, folder 204 (Box 23, Folder 698)
  - Box 5, folder 244 (Box 23, Folder 699)
  - Box 5, folder 281 (Box 23, Folder 700)
  - Box 7, folder 336 (Box 23, Folder 701)
  - Box 8, folder 349 (Box 23, Folder 702)
  - Box 9, folder 355 (Box 23, Folder 703)
  - Box 10, folder 370 (Box 23, Folder 704)
  - Box 10, folder 371 (Box 23, Folder 705)
  - Box 10, folder 372 (Box 23, Folder 706)
  - Box 11, folder 395 (Box 23, Folder 707)
  - Box 12, folder 407 (Box 23, Folder 708)
  - Box 12, folders 409, 412, 414, 416, 418-420, 422, 426, 428-429, 446 (Box 23, Folder 709)
  - Box 13, folder 480 (Box 23, Folder 710)
  - Box 13, folder 483 (Box 23, Folder 711)
  - Box 14, folders 539, 560 (Box 23, Folder 712)
  - Box 14, folders 565, 567-569, 572, 574-576 (Box 23, Folder 713)
  - Box 14, folders 579-580, 588, 592, 594 (Box 23, Folder 714)
  - Box 15, folder 601 (Box 23, Folder 715)
  - Box 15, folder 602 (Box 23, Folder 716)
  - Box 15, folder 604 (Box 23, Folder 717)
  - Box 15, folder 611 (Box 23, Folder 718)
  - Box 15, folder 612 (Box 23, Folder 719)
  - Box 15, folder 613 (Box 23, Folder 720)
  - Box 16, folder 618 (Box 23, Folder 721)
  - Box 16, folder 620 (Box 23, Folder 722)
  - Box 16, folder 621 (Box 23, Folder 723)
  - Box 17, folder 624 (Box 23, Folder 724)
  - Box 17, folder 634 (Box 23, Folder 725)
  - Box 17, folder 635 (Box 23, Folder 726)
  - Box 21, folder 643 (Box 23, Folder 727)
  - Box 21, folder 644 (Box 23, Folder 728)
  - Box 21, folder 648 (Box 23, Folder 729)
  - Box 21, folder 666 (Box 23, Folder 730)
  - Box 21, folder 667 (Box 23, Folder 731)
  - Box 21, folder 668 (Box 23, Folder 732)
  - Box 21, folder 672 (Box 23, Folder 733)
  - Box 21, folder 673 (Box 23, Folder 734)
  - Box 17, folder 631 (Box 24, Folder 735)
  - Box 17, folder 638 (Box 24a, Folder 736)
  - Box 3, folder 127 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 737)
  - Box 4, folder 226 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 738)
  - Box 5, folder 266 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 739)
  - Box 8, folder 347 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 740)
  - Box 10, folder 374 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 741)
  - Box 10, folder 382 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 742)
  - Box 12, folders 410-411, 413, 415, 417, 421, 423-425, 427, 430-433 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 743)
  - Box 12, folders 434-445 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 744)
  - Box 13, folder 495 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 745)
  - Box 13, folder 499 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 746)
  - Box 14, folder 583 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 747)
  - Box 14, folder 589 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 748)
  - Box 14, folder 593 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 749)
  - Box 14, folder 596 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 750)
  - Box 15, folder 598 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 751)
  - Box 15, folder 599 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 752)
  - Box 15, folder 600 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 753)
  - Box 15, folder 605 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 754)
  - Box 15, folder 606 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 755)
  - Box 15, folder 607 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 756)
  - Box 15, folder 608 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 757)
  - Box 15, folder 609 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 758)
  - Box 15, folder 610 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 759)
  - Box 15, folder 614 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 760)
  - Box 16, folder 615 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 761)
  - Box 16, folder 616 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 762)
  - Box 16, folder 617 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 763)
  - Box 16, folder 622 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 764)
  - Box 17, folder 626 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 765)
  - Box 21, folder 653 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 766)
  - Box 21, folder 655 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 767)
  - Box 21, folder 661 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 768)
  - Box 21, folder 663 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 769)
  - Box 21, folder 664 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 770)
  - Box 21, folder 665 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 771)
  - Box 21, folder 669 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 772)
  - Box 21, folder 670 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 773)
  - Box 21, folder 671 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 774)
  - Box 22, folder 688 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 775)
  - Box 22, folders 689, 691 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 776)
  - Box 10, folder 381 (Box Bsd, folder 777)